A Guide to the Liaison Office Records of Virginia Governor George F. Allen, 1994-1998
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Liaison Office Records of Virginia Governor George F. Allen, 1994-1998
The Library of Virginia
35867
1.53 cu. ft. (3 boxes)
Virginia. Governor (1994-1998: Allen)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred by Georgia Root, Assistant Secretary of the Commonwealth, Richmond, Virginia, 22 June 1998.
Biographical/Historical Information
The Virginia General Assembly created the Virginia Liaison Office (VLO) in 1978 to serve as "an institutional and organizational link" between the Commonwealth of Virginia and the federal government. The Liaison Office is charged with monitoring and influencing federal legislation of interest to the Commonwealth. The VLO is located in Washington, D.C. and because of its close proximity, its employees maintain a network of contacts throughout all branches of the federal government.
George Felix Allen was born March 8, 1952 in Whittier, California to famed NFL football coach George H. Allen and his wife Henrietta (Lumbroso) Allen. He graduated from the University of Virginia in 1971 and the University of Virginia School of Law in 1977. Allen served in the Virginia House of Delegates from 1982-1991 and served a short term in the U.S. House of Delegates in the early 1990s. In November 1993, Allen beat Attorney General Mary Sue Terry to become Governor. Governor Allen served until January 1998 and was succeeded by Governor James S. Gilmore. Governor Allen has been married to Susan (Brown) Allen since 1986 and they have three children, Forrest, Tyler, and Brooke. The family resides in Mount Vernon, Virginia.
Scope and Content
Contains files which document the functions of the Virginia Liaison Office (VLO) in Washington, D.C. Files include testimonies of Virginia officials before the federal government, and cover topics such as Medicaid, the devolution of the Employment Security System, and education policy. Also included are briefing packets from all meetings of the National Governors' Association attended by Governor Allen and/or members of the Liaison Office.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. General Files
Series II. National Governors' Association Files
Contents List
- Series I. General Files, 1994-1998., Extent: 15 folders. (Box 1)
  Includes files relating to the functions of the Virginia Liaison Office, which coordinates activities between the Commonwealth and federal government. This series includes documents pertaining to specific commissions and associations, as well as testimonies of state officials before the federal government. Other topics covered here are Medicaid, legislative and regulatory priorities, and education policy.
  Arranged by subject.
  - National Governors' Association: Policy Regarding Individuals with Disabilities Act (I.D.E.A.). (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - National Education Entity (N.E.E.) Policy. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Southern Governors' Association. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Southern Governors' Association Urban Revitalization Conference (Newport News/Hampton, Virginia), 1997. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Southern Governors' Association 63rd Meeting, 1997. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Federal Mandate Report, 1998. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Virginia Officials' Testimonies Before the Federal Government, 1995. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Officials' Testimonies Before the Federal Government, 1996. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Virginia Officials' Testimonies Before the Federal Government, 1997. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Appalachian Regional Commission: Summary of Minutes. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Appalachian Regional Commission: Investment Packages. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Medicaid. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Devolution of the Employment Security System (Federal Unemployment Tax Act). (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 104th Congress Legislative Wrap-up (Virginia Liaison Office). (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Federal Legislative and Regulatory Priorities (Virginia Liaison Office). (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Series II. National Governors' Association Files, 1994-1998., Extent: 28 folders. (Box 1-3.)
  Includes briefing materials from the biannual meetings of the National Governors' Association (NGA) attended by Governor Allen and/or members of the Liaison Office. Briefing books contain agendas, news releases, reports, and other material pertinent to the topics discussed at each meeting.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - National Governors' Association Briefing Book (Winter Meeting), 1994 January. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - National Governors' Association Briefing Book (Winter Meeting), 1994 January. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - National Governors' Association Briefing Book (Winter Meeting), 1994 January. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - National Governors' Association Briefing Book (Summer Meeting), 1994 July. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - National Governors' Association Briefing Book (Summer Meeting), 1994 July. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - National Governors' Association Briefing Book (Summer Meeting), 1994 July. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - National Governors' Association Briefing Book (Winter Meeting), 1995 January. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - National Governors' Association Briefing Book (Winter Meeting), 1995 January. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - National Governors' Association Briefing Book (Winter Meeting), 1995 January. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - National Governors' Association Briefing Book (Summer Meeting), 1995 July-August. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - National Governors' Association Briefing Book (Summer Meeting), 1995 July-August. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - National Governors' Association Briefing Book (Summer Meeting), 1995 July-August. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - National Governors' Association Briefing Book (Summer Meeting), 1995 July-August. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - National Governors' Association Briefing Book (Winter Meeting), 1996 February. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - National Governors' Association Briefing Book (Winter Meeting), 1996 February. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - National Governors' Association Briefing Book (Winter Meeting), 1996 February. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - National Governors' Association Briefing Book (Summer Meeting), 1996 July. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - National Governors' Association Briefing Book (Summer Meeting), 1996 July. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - National Governors' Association Briefing Book (Summer Meeting), 1996 July. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - National Governors' Association Briefing Book (Summer Meeting), 1996 July. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - National Governors' Association Briefing Book (Winter Meeting), 1997 February. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - National Governors' Association Briefing Book (Winter Meeting), 1997 February. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - National Governors' Association Briefing Book (Winter Meeting), 1997 February. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - National Governors' Association Briefing Book (Winter Meeting), 1997 February. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - National Governors' Association Briefing Book (Summer Meeting), 1997 July. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - National Governors' Association Briefing Book (Summer Meeting), 1997 July. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - National Governors' Association Briefing Book (Summer Meeting), 1997 July. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - National Governors' Association Briefing Book (Summer Meeting), 1997 July. (Box 3, Folder 4)